## YONGBO WANG

# Shapingba District, Chongqing, China (+86) 136-3799-5210

HomePage: https://yongbowin.github.io/ LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/yongbo-wang/ yongbowin@outlook.com

## **PROFILE:**

Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing (NLP) professional with over 1 year of internship experience. Good at commonly used Machine Learning algorithms and like to study cutting-edge theories and algorithms for machine learning and deep learning. Master's candidate in Computer Science with a concentration in Cloud Computing. Double bachelor degree in Computer Science and Business Administration. Sensitive to numbers and good at using math and programming to solve practical problems. Title of *Network Engineer*. Strong background in programming.

## **EDUCATION:**

Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology (SIAT), Chinese Academy of Sciences Dec 2017-present

- As a visiting student at the Global Center for Big Mobile Intelligence (BMI)
- Supervisor: Prof. Qiang Qu and Prof. Min Yang
- Research area: Natural Language Processing

## MPhil | College of Computer Science, Chongqing University

Sep 2015-present

- Major in Computer Science and Technology (recommended postgraduate)
- Supervisor: Prof. Yunni Xia
- Research area: Resource scheduling based on Cloud Computing

# **Bachelor** | College of Computer Science, Chongqing University

Sep 2011

- Major in Computer Science and Technology
- Minor in Business Administration (Supervisor: Prof. Wei Yan)

## **RESEARCH INTERESTS:**

Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Deep Learning

#### **PUBLICATIONS:**

- Weiling Li, Yongbo Wang, Yuandou Wang, Yunni Xia, Kunyin Guo, Quanwang Wu, Qingsheng Zhu, An energy-aware and under-SLA-constraints VM consolidation strategy based on the optimal matching method accepted by International Journal of Web Services Research (IJWSR) Volume 14, Issue 4 (IJWSR), IF0.667, 2017.
- YongBuo Wang, HaiChuan Zhang, KunYin Guo, Yunni Xia\*, WeiLing Li, *Stochastic performance analysis of unreliable IaaS clouds* accepted by Proceedings of S2 International Conference on Internet of Things(ICIOT), 2016.

#### AI RELATED COMPETITION:

We won **the second place** in the finals in the Intelligent Investment Adviser Game of the Big Data and Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Entrepreneurship Contest of 2017. This is one of the competitions about machine learning and NLP in China.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Natural Language Processing Intern, BMI, SIAT, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Dec 2017-present

• The question answering system of the law (on-going)

## YONGBO WANG

Shapingba District, Chongqing, China (+86) 136-3799-5210

HomePage: https://yongbowin.github.io/ LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/yongbo-wang/ yongbowin@outlook.com

Machine Learning & NLP Intern, Aizhihui Technology Co., Ltd., Shenzhen, China Jul 2016-Nov 2017

- Full text search of financial news, research reports and announcements of listed companies, and log analysis, the project based on Elasticsearch, Kafka, Logstash, Zookeeper and Kibana.
- The Chaorder System. Using NLP, Machine Learning, Word2Vec and ECKGs technologies.
- A chinese version of ECKGs.
- As project leader, developed the AITouJiang based on Wechat Official Account.
- As the principal person, started building public and private cloud servers from scratch. Responsible for server deployment and later maintenance.

Web Developer Intern, Chongqing Lingdao Technology Co. Ltd., Chongqing, China Jul 2015-Oct 2015

- ChunJi Micro Mall project.
- Holiday bargaining program project.
- Music Album project.

## **OTHER PROJECTS:**

Teaching Management System project	Spring 2016
WeChat Medical System project	Spring 2016
Power Construction Corporation of Chongqing project	Spring 2015

# **SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS:**

- **2nd place**, The Intelligent Investment Adviser Game of the Big Data and Artificial Intelligence Innovation and Entrepreneurship Contest of 2017.
- 2nd prize, Scholarship, Chongqing University (2017).
- 2nd prize, Scholarship, Chongging University (2016).
- 2nd prize, Chongqing Division, China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling (2013).
- National Endeavor Scholarship (top 5%) (2012).
- 2nd prize, Scholarship, Chongqing University (2012).

## **SKILLS:**

Python, Java, Shell, Linux, Docker, Hadoop, HBase, Sqoop, Pig, Elasticsearch, Tensorflow, MySQL, MongoDB, SVN, GitLab, Django, Web frameworks and shills (Django, SpringMVC, Struts2, HTML, Javascript, Ajax).

**Others:** Demonstrated team player. Work well with a multi-cultural and diverse work force. Thrives in collaborative environments.